KALOYAN DIMITROV

k.y.dimitrov@outlook.com | (+44) 7549 141599 | www.linkedin.com/in/kal-dimitrov

PROFILE

A Computer Science graduate with a global perspective, hailing from Bulgaria and currently living, working, and studying in the UK since 2016. Valuing reliability, integrity, and sustainable development when facing challenges, passionate about technology and its potential to improve lives, it is a mission of mine to contribute to technology sector by creating original and memorable experiences while remaining committed to ethical practices, innovation, and responsible technological advancement.

SKILLS

Soft: Teamwork, Problem-solver, Flexible, Creative, Proactive. User-Oriented, Hard-Working

Technical: Java, C++, C#, Full-stack, Python, R, SQL

Languages: English (Fluent), Bulgarian (Native), Russian (Basic), German (Basic)

Software Experience: Visual Studio, Visual Paradigm, SSMS, SSRS, PowerBI, IntelliJ IDEA, CLion and more

EDUCATION

City, University of London

BSc (Hons), Computer Science with Games Technology with Placement

Sep 2019 - Jul 2023

Final Year

- Relevant coursework in Advanced Games Technology, Functional Programming, Artificial Intelligence, Agents and Multi-Agent Systems, Computer Graphics
- Technical Skills: C++, Haskell, Python

Placement Year

- · Soft Skills: Critical Thinking, Business Intelligence, Data Analysis
- · Technical Skills: SQL, R, Excel

Second Year

- Relevant coursework in Object-Oriented Analysis and Design, Data Structures and Algorithms, C++, Computer Networks, Team Project, Games Technology
- Technical Skills: C++, UML

First Year

- Relevant coursework in Algorithms, Data Structures, Data Modelling, Object-Oriented Programming, CPU Scheduling,
 2D Computer Game, Website
- Technical Skills: Java, MySQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, jQuerry, Bootstrap, Bash/Shell, Microsoft Office

Wimbledon School of English, London, England

Oct 2018

Academic IELTS: Grade 6

- · Listening, Reading, Writing, Reading
- · Equivalent: A-levels

Vocational School "Simeon Veliki", Shumen, Bulgaria

Sep 2011 - May 2015

BTEC Level 3 in Business Informatics

- Framework Levels: RQF Level 3, SCQF Level 6, CQFW Level 3
- Equivalent: A-levels
- · Technical Skills: C++ Basics, MS Office

PROJECTS

Clty, University of London | Computer Graphics | Star Trek Route Game

Feb 2023 - Apr 2023

- Designed and devised an interactive demonstration of a racing game for the holodeck simulation aboard the USS Enterprise with OpenGL 4.0 and C++.
- Accomplished a Catmull-Rom spline with C continuity to define the track, ensuring smooth transitions between control points.
- Accomplished camera views using enumerations and switches in C++, utilizing TNB-frame and Frenet-Serret formulae to enable players to experience first-person, third-person, side-view, top-down, and free-camera perspectives.

Clty, University of London | Introduction to AI | Natural Disaster Prediction

- Oct 2022 Dec 2022
- Pioneered an approach to predicting natural disasters by analysing and preprocessing a big dataset with python, resulting in some accurate predictions of time, location, and type of disaster.
- · Delivered a well-described dataset and conducted exploratory analysis with python for feature selection.
- Performed interpolation to handle missing values for some features with python and incremented the dataset by determining geolocation of events.
- Managed the standardized data and calculated a measure of the total impact of disasters. This facilitated analysis with neural networks and one hot encoder.

Clty, University of London | Team Project | BAPERS software

Jan 2021 - Apr 2021

- Adopted roles of a system designer, analyst and tester responsible for elicitation of customer requirements, analysis and specification, system design process and writing test plans, testing system and its components for a team of 7.
- Produced two detailed reports, one outlining the requirements and another the system design to devise the software
 architecture. Designed multiple diagrams, including Use-Case, Class, and Deployment diagrams, to provide UML
 documentation.
- Conducted thorough internal testing as part of a 7-member team to guarantee the dependability and resilience of the system.

EXPERIENCE

Epsom and St Helier University Hospitals NHS Data Analyst Trust, London, England

Sep 2021 - Sep 2022

- · Mined data from primary and secondary sources, recognized and formatted it for statistical analysis.
- · Interpreted trends and patterns in data for diagnostic support and identified process improvements in clinical areas.
- Completed daily tasks related to data analysis, including mining data with SQL, producing SSRS reports, and analysing data with PowerBI.
- Led on and contributed to projects for clinical areas, providing digital analytic services with SSMS and SSRS to front-line clinicians.
- · Kept up with technology, systems, and processes to improve existing skills and stayed updated with new developments.
- Generated various reports for clinical colleagues and developed procedural documentation for several daily and monthly tasks.
- Took part in daily group meetings pertaining to the NHS and relevant news.

Bright Network, London, England

Technology Intern

Jun 2020 - Dec 2020

- Adopted role of a Product Manager for a large UK Bank, developed a plan with MS Office to release Facial Verification into customer banking application sign-in process.
- Delivered Project summary, User story summary, Project management plan and Communications plan documents using MS Office.

Self Employed, London, England

Handyman

Aug 2017 - Sep 2019

• Undertook various jobs from private clients & agencies.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Vocational School "Simeon Veliki"

· Certificate of Vocational Education (Business Informatics Specialist) | May 2015 - Present

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

Team sports - (volleyball, basketball, tennis.) Solo sports - (swimming, jogging, walking.) Reading - (Comics, Horror, Sci-Fi.) Building things - (Construction related.)